const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is the end-product of purine metabolism?","answers":[{"option":"Uric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Guanine","bool":false},{"option":"Uracil","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The nephron is the functional unit of the kidney responsible for the filtration of plasma. It consists of which two major components?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule and distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Renal corpuscle and loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Renal tubule and collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Renal corpuscle and renal tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule and loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the value of the glomerular filtration rate below which it is classified as an end-stage renal disease (ESRD)?","answers":[{"option":"60 mL/min","bool":false},{"option":"30 mL/min","bool":false},{"option":"75 mL/min","bool":false},{"option":"15 mL/min","bool":true},{"option":"45 mL/min","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is a carbonic anhydrase inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Torsemide","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":true},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":false},{"option":"Bumetanide","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following parts of the nephron is involved in the facultative reabsorption of water?","answers":[{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Duct of Bellini","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 10-year-old girl complained of increasing fatigue and passing dark-colored urine for one week. She had a sore throat two weeks ago. On physical examination, there is no fever, and blood pressure is 140/90 mmHg. Laboratory studies show her serum creatinine is 2.8 mg/dL and urea nitrogen 24 mg/dL. Urinalysis shows 2+ blood, 1+ protein, no glucose, and no ketones. Microscopic urinalysis shows dysmorphic RBCs. A renal biopsy on microscopic examination shows glomerular hypercellularity, with polymorphonuclear leukocytes (PMNs) present. Electron microscopy shows subepithelial electron-dense humps. Which of the following laboratory findings is most likely to be present in this girl?","answers":[{"option":"Antibody to double stranded DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated antistreptolysin O (ASO) titer","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-glomerular basement membrane antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Elevated serum glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Positive C3 nephritogenic factor","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 38-year-old woman came with severe suprapubic pain. Urine analysis showed neutrophils without a cast, cloudy, and foul-smelling urine. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hydronephrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute cystitis","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic cystitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pyelonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 10-year-boy is admitted to the ward with the complaint of urinary retention. A Foley catheter is passed to relieve the retention. How much length of catheter should be inserted before inflating the balloon of catheter?","answers":[{"option":"3-5 cm of catheter length","bool":false},{"option":"When the urine starts flowing","bool":false},{"option":"Half the length of catheter","bool":false},{"option":"Just tip of the catheter","bool":false},{"option":"Entire length of the catheter","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A second-year medical student is looking at the histology slide of tissue with small-caliber lined by transitional epithelium and also observes three layers of smooth muscles in its wall.  He is looking at a slide of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter","bool":true},{"option":"Prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary bladder","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 30-year-old pregnant lady is going for an emergency cesarean section. She is being catheterized before the procedure. Which one is the most recurrent complication of urinary catheterization?","answers":[{"option":"Pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":true},{"option":"Nephrolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 32-year-old lady comes to the ultrasound department for an antenatal scan which shows bilateral hydronephrosis, hydro-ureters, and a distended urinary bladder with a keyhole sign in the fetus. The fetus is suspected with a case of posterior urethral valves. She is advised to have a post-natal checkup of the baby. What is the investigation of choice in this particular case?","answers":[{"option":"Kidney, ureter, and bladder (KUB) X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Voiding cystourethrogram (VCUG)","bool":true},{"option":"Computed tomography scan (CT scan)","bool":false},{"option":"Repeat ultrasound KUB + Prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is a complication of acute pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Papillary necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Necrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecystitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic renal faillure","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 35-year-old male presents with features of nephrotic syndrome. In addition, there is microscopic haematuria. Renal biopsy shows partial sclerosis affecting some of the glomeruli. Sclerosed areas show IgM and C3 on immunofluorescence. What is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Acute post infectious glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 4-year-old girl presents with severe pitting edema. Further investigations show hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.8 g proteinuria. Biopsy confirms the renal disease. Which of the following best describes the pathophysiology of proteinuria in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Antiâ€“glomerular basement membrane (anti-GBM) antibodies cross reacting with alveolar basement membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent formation in the glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Excess dietary protein intake","bool":false},{"option":"Tubulointerstitial damage","bool":false},{"option":"Derangement in glomerular capillary walls","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 4-year-old girl is brought to the hospital with complaints of continuous dribbling of urine. On examination, the urine was coming out of the vagina. The possible cause of this embryological anomaly may be due to which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Formation of vaginal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Ureter opening into the base of urinary bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter opening into the urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter opening into cloaca","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter opening into paramesonephric duct","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is formed as a result of deamination of cytosine?","answers":[{"option":"Adenine","bool":false},{"option":"Methyl cytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Uracil","bool":true},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following clinical symptoms differentiates pyelonephritis from cystitis?","answers":[{"option":"Dysuria","bool":false},{"option":"Hematuria","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":true},{"option":"Polyuria","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is a method to excrete excess water?","answers":[{"option":"Increased respiratory rate","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Polyuria","bool":true},{"option":"Oliguria","bool":false},{"option":"Sweating","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 40-year-old businesswoman came to the outpatient department for the workup of her recurrent renal stone disease. She has already undergone multiple investigations and now she is insisting to go for magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). How will you counsel her that for her particular disease, MRI is not a suitable modality?","answers":[{"option":"MRI works under the principle of magnetism","bool":false},{"option":"No ionization radiation burden is present in MRI","bool":false},{"option":"MRI is an expensive modality","bool":false},{"option":"MRI reporting is difficult","bool":false},{"option":"Calcification/calcific densities are detected with difficulty by MRI","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 2nd-year student is studying kidney anatomy and finds out that there are some structures anterior to the right kidney. Which of the following is not found anterior to the right kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Pylorus","bool":true},{"option":"2nd part of duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic flexure","bool":false},{"option":"Right colic flexure","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 43-year-old man complains of malaise for 3 weeks. On examination, his blood pressure is 150/95 mm Hg, and presents with pitting edema of the lower extremities. Urinalysis shows no glucose, blood, ketones, nitrite, or urobilinogen, and the microscopic urinalysis reveals no RBC/HPF and only 1 WBC/HPF, 24-hour urine protein is 4.1 gm, serum creatinine is 3.5 mg/dL with urea nitrogen of 38 mg/dL. His hepatitis B surface antigen is positive. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Post streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 5-year-old boy presents with generalized edema and periorbital edema. Further investigations show hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.7 g proteinuria. Which of the following conditions is the most likely cause in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":true},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 5-year-old boy has had swelling around his eyes for one week, and he has been lethargic. On examination, he has periorbital edema. His temperature is 37Â°C, pulse is 75 bpm, respiratory rate is 22/minute, and blood pressure is 140/90 mmHg. Urine examination shows a specific gravity of 1.010 and a pH of 6.5, with 4+ protein, no glucose, no blood, no casts, and no ketones. Microscopic urinalysis exhibits fat bodies, but no leukocytes or erythrocytes. He improves with corticosteroid therapy. Which of the following is the most likely lesion in the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperplastic arteriosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular crescent formation","bool":false},{"option":"Immune complex deposition in the mesangium","bool":false},{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Effacement of podocyte foot processes","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"During degradation of purine nucleotides to uric acid, inosine monophosphate and guanosine monophosphate are broken down by which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Ribonucleotide reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenosine deaminase","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"5'-nucleotidase","bool":true},{"option":"Guanylate kinase","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Aspartate enters the tricarboxylic acid cycle (TCA cycle) in the form of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Oxaloacetate","bool":true},{"option":"Succinic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-ketoglutarate","bool":false},{"option":"Citrate","bool":false},{"option":"Fumarate","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella species","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"Enterococcus faecalis","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 6-year-old boy presents with generalized edema and periorbital edema. Further investigations show hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.6 g proteinuria. Renal biopsy and electron microscopy are carried out. Which of the following electron microscopic features do you expect to find in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Subepithelial humps","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of foot processes, no deposits","bool":true},{"option":"Dense mesangial deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Subendothelial deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Linear deposits of IgG in the glomerular basement membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Synthetic compound allopurinol given to treat hyperuricemia is an analog of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":true},{"option":"Orotic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Thymine","bool":false},{"option":"Inosine","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is diagnostic of acute gout?","answers":[{"option":"Acute phase reactants","bool":false},{"option":"Monosodium urate crystals on joint aspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Serum uric acid levels","bool":false},{"option":"Radiology of joint","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A child after a streptococcal infection presents 10 days later with hypertension, hematuria, edema, and sometimes oliguria. There appear to be elevated titers of anti-streptolysin O antibodies. What is the key morphological feature of his disease?","answers":[{"option":"Humps and deposition of IgG and C3","bool":true},{"option":"Humps","bool":false},{"option":"Deposition of IgG and C3","bool":false},{"option":"Deposition of IgM and C3","bool":false},{"option":"Spike and dome appearance","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A filterability of 1.0 means that the substance is filtered as freely as water, whereas a filterability of 0.75 means that the substance is filtered only 75%. Which of the following substance has a filterability of only 75 percent as rapidly as water?","answers":[{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Myoglobin","bool":true},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A normal 70 kg human must excrete about how many milliosmoles of solute each day?","answers":[{"option":"400","bool":false},{"option":"200","bool":false},{"option":"1000","bool":false},{"option":"600","bool":true},{"option":"800","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the research study design in which diseased people are selected and then compared with the non-diseased people to find out the risk factors of the disease called?","answers":[{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":false},{"option":"Case report study","bool":false},{"option":"Case control study","bool":true},{"option":"Cohort study","bool":false},{"option":"Case series study","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is a water molecule with an electrical charge distributed asymmetrically about its structure referred to as?","answers":[{"option":"Pentapolar","bool":false},{"option":"Unipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Tripolar","bool":false},{"option":"Dipolar","bool":true},{"option":"Tetrapolar","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A young male presented in a dehydrated state of moderate degree. His renal function is normal but he is unable to take fluid orally because of drowsiness and vomiting. Which of the following intravenous fluids is preferable to start first?","answers":[{"option":"3% saline","bool":false},{"option":"Distilled water","bool":false},{"option":"1/3 saline","bool":false},{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":false},{"option":"5% dextrose","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"About 35% of the filtered load of sodium chloride is reabsorbed from which part of the nephron?","answers":[{"option":"Thin limb - loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Thick ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Amina has recently completed her FCPS and now she is pursuing her career as a specialist. She was passionate about this field and always wanted to serve society and live a meaningful life. Which of the following approach of happiness most likely focuses on meaning and self-realization?","answers":[{"option":"Psychological well-being","bool":false},{"option":"Eudemonia","bool":true},{"option":"Hedonism","bool":false},{"option":"Happiness","bool":false},{"option":"Subjective well being","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the alkaline nature of the extracellular fluid and acidic urine termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Phenyl ketonuria","bool":false},{"option":"Paradoxical aciduria","bool":true},{"option":"Amino aciduria","bool":false},{"option":"Glucosuria","bool":false},{"option":"Ketonuria","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"An adult male had a road traffic accident and went into a hypovolemic shock due to blood loss. Which intravenous fluid is preferable to start as initial available therapy in an emergency?","answers":[{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Haemaccel","bool":true},{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acid solution","bool":false},{"option":"5% dextrose water","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In chronic renal failure, anemia develops due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Erythropoetin deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Blood loss","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow toxins","bool":false},{"option":"Red cell destruction","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow fibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Considering the normal urine composition, what is the water content of it in percentage?","answers":[{"option":"75%","bool":false},{"option":"95%","bool":true},{"option":"85%","bool":false},{"option":"80%","bool":false},{"option":"90%","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A decrease in sodium chloride levels causes the macula densa to do which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Dilatation of efferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of juxtaglomerular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dilatation of afferent arterioles","bool":true},{"option":"Contraction of mesangial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of renin","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Disturbance in the renal reabsorption of bicarbonates in the proximal tubules leads to which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrogen retention","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypochloremia","bool":false},{"option":"Acidic urine","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"During a tutorial class on the microscopic structure of the kidney, specific features of each part of the nephron were being discussed. Which of the following is mismatched?","answers":[{"option":"Visceral layer of Bowman's capsule - podocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Thin segment of Henle's loop - simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal tubule cells - many mitochondria; an ion-pumping cell","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal layer of Bowman's capsule - simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Distal tubule cells - brush border","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which is true about creatinine during glomerular filtration at normal levels?","answers":[{"option":"Secreted by the tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Excreted by the tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Neither secreted nor reabsorbed by the tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Secreted and reabsorbed by the tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorbed by the tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which one of the following is true about the epithelium of navicular fossa of glans penis?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinizing epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinizing epithelium","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following factor causes an increase in the secretion of antidiuretic hormone (ADH)?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in plasma osmolarity","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Intake of alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in blood volume","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding acute kidney injury (AKI)?","answers":[{"option":"Often reversible","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium levels are high","bool":false},{"option":"Always needs dialysis","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound shows small kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia is a predominant feature","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Where does the hilum of the left kidney lie?","answers":[{"option":"The subcostal plane","bool":false},{"option":"The interspinous plane","bool":false},{"option":"The junction of midclavicular line and the transtubercular plane","bool":false},{"option":"The transpyloric plane, 5 cm from the median plane","bool":true},{"option":"The transtubercular plane, 5 cm from the median plane","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"If plasma colloidal osmotic pressure is 40 mmHg, renal capillary pressure is 60 mmHg, and Bowman's capsule hydrostatic pressure is 18 mmHg, which of the following effect occurs in the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Afferent arteriolar dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent arteriolar dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of macula densa","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) is increased","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular filtration rate (GFR) is reduced","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In a 60-year-old diabetic patient, a routine lab investigation shows hemoglobin: 8.2 gm/dL, creatinine (Cr): 5.0 mg/dL, calcium (Ca): 6.7 mg/dL, phosphate(PO4): 5.2 mg/dL, with small kidneys on ultrasound. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Acute kidney injury","bool":false},{"option":"Acute interstitial nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic kidney disease","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In a patient with severe dehydration, the plasma osmolality increases. This is corrected by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Antidiuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in protein intake","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin-II","bool":false},{"option":"Increased intake of glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which one of the following correctly states the osmolarity of the fluid entering  the proximal convoluted tubules?","answers":[{"option":"400 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"800 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"300 mOsm/L","bool":true},{"option":"1200 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"100 mOsm/L","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of these is present on urinalysis in a patient with glomerulonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Hyaline cast","bool":false},{"option":"Granular cast","bool":false},{"option":"Red cell cast","bool":true},{"option":"Renal tubular cell cast","bool":false},{"option":"White cell cast","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is true for the overhydration state?","answers":[{"option":"Osmotic pressure increases in extracellular fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus signals posterior pituitary to increase ADH (antidiuretic hormone) output","bool":false},{"option":"Osmoreceptors in hypothalamus are stimulated","bool":false},{"option":"Urine output decreases","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus signals posterior pituitary to decrease ADH (antidiuretic hormone) output","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In pyelonephritis, what is the diagnostic urinary finding?","answers":[{"option":"Pus cell cast","bool":true},{"option":"Pus cells","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cell cast","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the approximate value of the osmolarity of the interstitial fluid in renal medulla?","answers":[{"option":"600 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"1200 mOsm/L","bool":true},{"option":"200 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"800 mOsm/L","bool":false},{"option":"400 mOsm/L","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which one of the following confirms the diagnosis of gout?","answers":[{"option":"Increased uric acid excretion in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Redness and pain in joints","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of urate crystals in the synovial fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Renal stones","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In response to acidosis, the kidneys may enhance which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Secretion of HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrogen retention","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of H+ ions","bool":true},{"option":"Secretion of Na+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of K+ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In response to alkalosis, the kidneys may enhance which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Nitrogen retention","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of HCO3- ions","bool":true},{"option":"Secretion of H+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of Na+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion of K+ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In a detailed urine report, dipstick mechanism checks for which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Infecting organism","bool":false},{"option":"Protein and glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Casts","bool":false},{"option":"Crystals","bool":false},{"option":"Cells","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Renal retention of which of these ions is directly linked to an increase in extracellular fluid volume?","answers":[{"option":"K+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ ions","bool":true},{"option":"HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"H+ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What percentage of total body water is contained in the intracellular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"60%","bool":false},{"option":"30%","bool":false},{"option":"40%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"70%","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Juxtaglomerular apparatus is a specialized structure located at the vascular pole of the glomerulus. Which of the following is true concerning the juxtaglomerular apparatus?","answers":[{"option":"The macula densa is part of the proximal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Lacis cells are the specialized smooth muscle cells","bool":true},{"option":"The juxtaglomerular (JG) cells are modified epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"The juxtaglomerular (JG) cells are found equally in both the afferent and efferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Macula densa cells secrete renin","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Juxtaglomerular apparatus is very important in blood pressure regulation. Which of the following structure is not its part?","answers":[{"option":"Podocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Juxtaglomerular cells (JG) cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macula densa","bool":false},{"option":"Polkissen cells","bool":false},{"option":"Extra glomerular mesangial cells","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Lymphatics of kidneys drain into which nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Testicular nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Pre aortic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral aortic nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial inguinal nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following organisms is responsible for xanthogranulomatous pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following does the least dilated part of male urethra develops from?","answers":[{"option":"Fusion of urethral folds","bool":false},{"option":"Phallic part of urogenital sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Allantois","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic part of urogenital sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Wolffian duct","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following steps comes after data collection?","answers":[{"option":"Formulate question","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothesis","bool":false},{"option":"Literature search","bool":false},{"option":"Development of research design","bool":false},{"option":"Data analysis","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the first step of research?","answers":[{"option":"Literature search","bool":false},{"option":"Formulate questions","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothesis","bool":true},{"option":"Data collection","bool":false},{"option":"Develop research design","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"How are membranous glomerulopathy and post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis similar?","answers":[{"option":"Both are self-limiting and transient renal diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Most commonly seen in children","bool":false},{"option":"Commonly associated with the nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Occur most frequently following an infectious disease","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular immune complex deposits","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In purine metabolism, what does the deamination of guanine yield?","answers":[{"option":"Cytidylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Uracil","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine","bool":true},{"option":"Methyl guanine","bool":false},{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Increase in which of the following characterizes metabolic alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma pH and increased lactate levels","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and decreased CO2 levels","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and increased respiratory rate","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and decrease in HCO3- levels","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma pH and increased plasma bicarbonate (HCO3-) levels","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Mrs. X, a 30-year-old, recently married female, presented with a breast lump for the first time in the clinic. The doctor listened to her attentively but was insensitive towards her symptoms and complications. The doctor did not say or discuss anything but advised her to get the list of investigations done. She returned from the clinic more apprehensive and confused. What do you think, could most likely address her apprehensions?","answers":[{"option":"An attribute of cultural sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"An attribute of empathy","bool":false},{"option":"By arranging an information care session","bool":true},{"option":"By offering emotional support","bool":false},{"option":"By addressing her misconceptions","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Mr. Mughees did not score well in the exam. He has pessimistic explanatory styles and attributed his failure to generalized bad luck i.e. 'I always had bad luck in all life situations' (stable and global attribution), which lead to him being depressed. Which one of the following could preferably explain the causes of negative events contrary to this pessimistic explanatory style?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Internal, stable","bool":false},{"option":"Internal, specific, unstable","bool":true},{"option":"External, global, stable","bool":false},{"option":"External, unstable, specific","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"On discussing histological features of the kidney, the students were asked about the location of macula densa. What is its location?","answers":[{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Renal pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Periureteric fascia is an extension of which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Paranephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Renal fascia","bool":true},{"option":"Perinephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Pararenal fat","bool":false},{"option":"Perirenal fat","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is carbamoyl phosphate a precursor of?","answers":[{"option":"Xanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Ionosine","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What causes the reabsorption of bicarbonates from renal tubules?","answers":[{"option":"Retention of acid metabolites","bool":false},{"option":"Low acid secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Raised PCO2","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased NH3 formation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased PCO2","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Reabsorption of sodium in renal tubules is associated with the exchange of which of these ions?","answers":[{"option":"Na+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"H+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"K+ ions","bool":true},{"option":"Cl- ions","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is not true regarding blood supply to the kidneys?","answers":[{"option":"Inter lobular arteries are end arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Afferent glomerular arterioles arise mostly form arcuate arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Renal circulation is of portal type","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney is divided into five vascular segments","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla receives blood mostly from efferent arterioles of glomeruli","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the approximate length of kidney?","answers":[{"option":"12 cm","bool":false},{"option":"10 cm","bool":true},{"option":"6-12 cm","bool":false},{"option":"8-9 cm","bool":false},{"option":"11-13 cm","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Regarding glomerular diseases, which of the following is most likely the pathogenesis of glomerulonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Complement proteins do not play an important role in the pathogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"TGF-Î² released during nephritis leads to glomerular basement membrane thickening","bool":true},{"option":"In immune complex mediated nephritis, the autoantigen is characteristically glomerular","bool":false},{"option":"A causal role of T-cells in the pathogenesis has been strongly established by researchers","bool":false},{"option":"The pattern of antibody deposition in anti - GBM disease is radial in pattern","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs is ineffective in Addison's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Amiloride","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocortisone","bool":false},{"option":"Triamterene","bool":false},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":true},{"option":"Bumetanide","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What are the regions of cortical parenchyma located between medullary pyramids rather than adjacent to the surface of the kidney called?","answers":[{"option":"Columns of Bertin","bool":true},{"option":"Papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Calyces","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary rays","bool":false},{"option":"Renal lobules","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is responsible for glucose reabsorption in the S1 segment of the proximal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"GLUT2 (glucose transporter-2)","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT3 (glucose transporter-3)","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT1 (glucose transporter-1)","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT1 (sodium-glucose cotransporter-1)","bool":false},{"option":"SGLT2 (sodium-glucose cotransporter-2)","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs should be used to decrease intracranial pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Mannitol","bool":true},{"option":"Fludrocortisone","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Midodrine","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is not present anterior to the urinary bladder?","answers":[{"option":"Pubic bones","bool":false},{"option":"Puboprostatic ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Body of uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Retropubic space","bool":false},{"option":"Pubo-vesical ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What does renal correction of acute hyperkalemia result in?","answers":[{"option":"Increased secretion of H+","bool":false},{"option":"Alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Increased secretion of Na+","bool":false},{"option":"Increased secretion of HCO3-","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Sodium retention through aldosterone-mediated renal regulation results in the elimination of which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"NH3+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ions","bool":false},{"option":"K+ ions","bool":true},{"option":"H+ ions","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Where do the stretch signals for bladder emptying mainly originate?","answers":[{"option":"Ureter","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus of urinary bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Body of the bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior urethra","bool":true}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following will increase the ability of the kidney to excrete concentrated urine?","answers":[{"option":"Increasing the rate of flow through the loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Decreasing the rate of blood flow through the medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Decreasing the permeability of the proximal tubule to water","bool":false},{"option":"Decreasing the permeability of the collecting duct to water","bool":false},{"option":"Decreasing the activity of the Na-K pump in the loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which type of transport facilitates the sodium absorption in distal convoluted tubule by Na pump across the basolateral membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Passive transport","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":true},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which structure is not related to the anterior surface of the right kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Right colic flexure","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":true},{"option":"Descending part of duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Suprarenal gland","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following provides arterial supply to the pelvic part of the ureter?","answers":[{"option":"Gonadal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vesical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac artery","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Renal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the compensatory mechanism in respiratory acidosis (increased PCO2)?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in plasma bicarbonate (HCO3-) concentration","bool":false},{"option":"Increased oxygen saturation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased levels of ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in plasma bicarbonate (HCO3-) concentration","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased respiratory rate","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following do the afferent arterioles arise from?","answers":[{"option":"Intralobar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Interlobular artery","bool":true},{"option":"Interlobar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Peritubular capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate artery","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The distal part of the male urethra in the glans of the penis is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral plate mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediate mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following can the nephron be best defined as?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose transporter","bool":false},{"option":"A structural and functional unit of kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Storage site of lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Site of ADH (antidiuretic hormone) production","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol synthesizing body","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the end product of purine metabolism in humans?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoxanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Urea","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Inositol","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The examination of a cross-section of kidneys shows the renal columns of Bertin. Which statement best defines the renal columns of Bertin?","answers":[{"option":"Cortical substance that extends into medulla","bool":true},{"option":"Medullary substance that extends into cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrons that are drained by a common collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Marks beginning of nephron","bool":false},{"option":"Convoluted parts of renal tubules","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following chemical substances inhibits the secretion of gastric acid?","answers":[{"option":"Gastrin","bool":false},{"option":"Secretin","bool":true},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric inhibitory peptide","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The greatest amount of hydrogen ion secreted by the proximal tubule is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Excretion of hydrogen ion","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorption of calcium ion","bool":false},{"option":"Excretion of potassium ion","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorption of phosphate ion","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorption of bicarbonate ion","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"In which of the following are Na-K-Cl cotransporters present in?","answers":[{"option":"Thick ascending limb of the loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Thin ascending limb of the loop of Henle","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the large space, lined by transitional epithelium, which funnels urine into the ureter called?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Hilum","bool":false},{"option":"Papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Calyx","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is the only part present in the medullary region?","answers":[{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the most sensitive indicator of glomerular function?","answers":[{"option":"Serum urea","bool":false},{"option":"Serum creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Serum ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Urea clearance","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine clearance","bool":true}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the normal glomerular capillary colloid osmotic pressure?","answers":[{"option":"18 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"32 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"70 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"60 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the normal PO2 level in arterial blood?","answers":[{"option":"22-26 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"<50 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":">100 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"85-90 mm of Hg","bool":true},{"option":"35-45 mm of Hg","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The osmolality of the proximal convoluted tubule is the same as that of plasma, due to the presence of water channels on the basolateral membrane that causes reabsorption of water. Which water channels are present in the basolateral membrane of proximal convoluted tubules?","answers":[{"option":"Aquaporin-5","bool":false},{"option":"Aquaporin-3","bool":false},{"option":"Aquaporin-1","bool":true},{"option":"Aquaporin-4","bool":false},{"option":"Aquaporin-2","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which part of the nephron exhibits brush border on microscopy?","answers":[{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Pars recta","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which enzyme catalyzes the rate-limiting step of pyrimidine biosynthesis in mammalian cells?","answers":[{"option":"Carbamoyl phosphate synthase II","bool":true},{"option":"Thymidylate synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartate transcarbamoylase","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxanthine-guanine phosphoribosyltransferase (HGPRT)","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The severe constriction of efferent arterioles affects glomerular filtration rate (GFR) by which one of the following changes?","answers":[{"option":"It has no effect on GFR","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases GFR by increasing colloid osmotic force","bool":true},{"option":"Increases renal blood flow by afferent arteriole vasodilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Increases GFR by increasing colloid osmotic force","bool":false},{"option":"Increases GFR by increasing renal flow","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The substance is freely filtered at the glomerular capillaries but is not excreted into the urine because all the filtered substance is reabsorbed from the tubules back into the blood. This pattern occurs for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bases","bool":false},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids and glucose","bool":true},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"This substance is freely filtered at the glomerular capillaries and is not reabsorbed, but additional quantities of this substance are secreted from the peritubular capillary blood into the renal tubules. Which substance is this?","answers":[{"option":"Inulin","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids and glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":true},{"option":"Organic acids and bases","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"This substance is freely filtered by the glomerular capillaries but is neither reabsorbed nor secreted. Therefore, its excretion rate is equal to the rate at which it was filtered. Which substance is this?","answers":[{"option":"Inulin","bool":true},{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Under the influence of parathyroid hormone, the renal reabsorption of calcium mainly occurs in which part of the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":true},{"option":"Renal papilla","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending thick limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa recta","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting ducts","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What are the vessels that connect glomerular capillaries with peritubular capillaries called?","answers":[{"option":"Afferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa recta","bool":false},{"option":"Peritubular capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Arcuate arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent arterioles","bool":true}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which reflex is initiated when the ureter is blocked by the stone resulting in intense pain?","answers":[{"option":"Vesico-ureteric reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Ureteric reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Reno-vesical reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Vesical reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Uretero-renal reflex","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is the correct sequence of branching pattern of renal arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Segmental artery > lobar artery > intralobular artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental artery > interlobar artery > lobar artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar artery > segmental artery > interlobar artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar artery > segmental artery > intralobular artery > arcuate artery","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental artery > lobar artery > interlobar artery > arcuate artery","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is not the part of renal filtration barrier?","answers":[{"option":"Continuous epithelium of glomerular capillaries","bool":true},{"option":"Podocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Basal lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Fenestrated endothelium of glomerular capillaries","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following study design is also called a snap shot study?","answers":[{"option":"Case control study","bool":false},{"option":"Case series","bool":false},{"option":"Cohort study","bool":false},{"option":"Case report study","bool":false},{"option":"Cross-sectional study","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Xanthine oxidase is catalytically important for the formation of uric acid along with which of these?","answers":[{"option":"H2O","bool":false},{"option":"HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"H2O2","bool":false},{"option":"CO2","bool":false},{"option":"O2","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the renal capillary pressure across the glomerular capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"50 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"20 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"30 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"60 mmHg","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"What is the major hormone involved in regulation of sodium and water balance in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Antidiuretic hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"The superior portion of the ureter drains into which of the following lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Internal iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral aortic nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Vesical nodes","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following can be seen in the renal sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Bowman's capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Renal pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following forms the outermost layer of the kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Only fat","bool":false},{"option":"Perinephric fat","bool":false},{"option":"Peritoneum","bool":false},{"option":"Renal fascia","bool":true}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is an acquired cause of vesicoureteral reflux in adults leading to urinary tract infection?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal cord lesions","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder stones","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney stones","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is not derived from ureteric bud?","answers":[{"option":"Ureter","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Renal pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following can not be used as a marker to measure glomerular filtration rate (GFR)?","answers":[{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Phenol red","bool":false},{"option":"Urea and nitrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Inulin","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is measured through the arterial blood gas (ABG) test?","answers":[{"option":"Anion gap","bool":false},{"option":"pH, pCO2 and pO2","bool":true},{"option":"Oxygen saturation","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine level","bool":false},{"option":"pCO2 and pO2","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following correctly describes 'informational care'?","answers":[{"option":"Provision of information to patients about disease","bool":false},{"option":"Provision of information to patients about drugs and their side effects","bool":false},{"option":"Provision of information to patients about doctors","bool":false},{"option":"Provision of information to patients about disease, drugs, and doctors","bool":true},{"option":"Provision of information to patients about drugs and doctors","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is most true for transplantation?","answers":[{"option":"Polycystic kidneys should be excluded from the list of allografts","bool":true},{"option":"HIV is the most contraindicated","bool":false},{"option":"Quality of life is increased after transplantation","bool":false},{"option":"Renal transplantation is reasonable for all end-stage renal diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Graft reaction occurs in poor patients","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A patient came to the outpatient department with frequent urinary discharge. A complete urinalysis on agar medium was done and bacteria were found to be non-lactose fermenter, gram -ve, rod-shaped with no signs of swarming movement. Which of the following could be the cause?","answers":[{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterococcus","bool":false},{"option":"E.coli","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":true},{"option":"Proteus vulgaris","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs is effective in decreasing K+ ion secretion in the distal convoluted tubule?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium-sparing diuretic","bool":true},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Thiazide diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Loop diuretics","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is involved in the counter-current multiplier mechanism of kidneys?","answers":[{"option":"Vasa recta","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Peritubular arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle","bool":true}]},{"id":137,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is the normal value of filtration fraction?","answers":[{"option":"10%","bool":false},{"option":"15%","bool":false},{"option":"7%","bool":false},{"option":"20%","bool":true},{"option":"5%","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following is not found anterior to the left kidney?","answers":[{"option":"Head of pancreas","bool":true},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Suprarenal gland","bool":false},{"option":"Looped jejenum","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic flexure","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following parts of the bladder expands when it is filled up completely?","answers":[{"option":"Trigone","bool":true},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Base","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A 20-year-old man is brought into the emergency as he has overdosed on morphine. On examination, he is unconscious, pupils are pinpoint and nonreactive. Several injection marks are also seen on his arms. What is the immediate treatment to be precise after seeing breathing, and circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Naloxone","bool":true},{"option":"Naloxone + gastric lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric lavage","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric lavage with tannic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Naloxone + pethidine","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"A couple married for four years was unable to conceive a pregnancy. A detailed analysis of the sperms of the husband revealed azoospermia. They were suggested to go for artificial insemination by a fertility specialist. Which type of procedure would best suit the couple?","answers":[{"option":"Artificial insemination donor","bool":true},{"option":"Artificial insemination homologous","bool":false},{"option":"Surrogacy","bool":false},{"option":"In vitro fertilization","bool":false},{"option":"Artificial insemination","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"2nd-year/renal/2020","question":"Which of the following hormones or autocoids can increase the glomerular filtration rate (GFR) by decreasing vascular resistance in the glomerular capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"Angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin I","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial derived nitric oxide","bool":true}]}]
export default arr